Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Pluto
Yamato, do you read?
Mayday! Mayday!
I understand.
So the Teron ship is called the Yamato.
However...
What an ugly ship that is. Not a bit of grace to it!
The Yamato is probably on its way here, to Plat.
We'll lure it in and destroy it.
Is there any guarantee they'll come here?
The planet bombs that turned their planet into a red husk
were launched here.
I see. Then this is a splendid chance for your inferior race,
of differently colored skin, to
demonstrate your loyalty to Gamilas.
We're every bit as loyal to the Empire as pure-blooded Gamilans!
That's what I want to see in a great Gamilas soldier.
I shall expect results. Garle Dessler!
Hail to our leader!
I long for those days when I fought for General Domel.
Indeed.
How is the scheduled strike coming?
Planet bomb 103 will launch shortly.
<Reflecting satellite 4. Deploying reflector.>
<Correcting angle +5 degrees.>
<Reflecting satellite 8. Deploying reflector.>
<Correcting angle +4 degrees.>
Correct for target errors -3.7.
Target sighted. Reflecting Satellite Cannon charging.
Chamber pressure rising.
Reflecting Satellite Cannon charging complete.
Fire!
Hitting 103.
103 has been ignited. Angle proper.
Accelerating at a speed of 17 gat.
103 is on a collision course for planet Teron.
Don't you think we could use this?
Edgeworth-Kuiper belt object EKB 637
has deviated from its course.
It's a planet bomb.
Demons.
No enemies within two light-seconds of us.
So you're standing in for Mori?
Nice to have another pretty girl around...
Stop staring. It's rude.
Then XO Sanada and Kodai are both off duty now, huh?
They're at the lab, looking at that Gamilas soldier.
Ah... Mori's there too then.
How does it feel to sit there?
I-It's fine...
This technology is amazing.
Nanomachines comprise this artificial organelle.
Do you know the composition of its epidermis?
The exterior is composed of soft tektite rubber.
They're a race of machines?
Why do you think that?
Why? Then what are these?
Androids.
I already knew that!
We can't say whether they're self-replicating machines,
or simply weapons modeled after humanoid life.
That's what the XO means.
Thank you.
But...
Now then,
our report's over, so we'll be going.
Hey...
No complaints... Go!
You're sure there were no survivors aboard the Yukikaze, right?
Yes.
Very well.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
You're concerned about him. Aren't you, sir?
I quite like that about you...
Which of them is the android?
He's like, I dunno...
A computer human! Or something.
That's just the way XO Sanada is.
Anyway...
Kodai...
What?
Thanks for everything back at Enceladus.
You protected us.
Well, it was my mission. Of course I did.
Right, of course.
Oh, did you know? About the Cosmo Zero that came to help us.
Someone named Yamamoto, from accounting, piloted it.
Since when are you a pilot?
I'll let it slide this time. But if you ever do that again...
It was the optimal course under those conditions.
Let me transfer to the pilot squad.
Are you going to try and avenge Akio?
No!
I have no right to decide that.
Only the captain does.
Sometimes, you know...
A locker this time?
Yeah, she just won't listen.
That sure is a stubborn locker...
Lieutenant Kato!
Um, if that pilot hadn't come,
it would've been really bad for us.
I think they saved our lives...
Oh, fine...
Um...
Attention all high-ranking officers.
All high-ranking officers, please meet in the main operations room.
Did I say something strange?
Heck if I know!
I had planned to avoid all unnecessary combat,
to get us to Iscandar as soon as possible.
But we cannot allow the continued existence of the Pluto base,
whose planet bombs have rendered the Earth a wasteland.
We shall destroy that base with everything we have.
After the Gamilans captured Pluto, they altered its environment.
It is now a dwarf planet with oceans.
The UN Cosmo Force has analyzed the movement of surface hot spots,
and determined that the base is most likely to be at one of these points.
We can't identify it with certainty?
Unfortunately not.
It's probable that they're using some kind of stealth shield around the base.
They aren't making this easy...
It's a major enemy base. We can expect heavy resistance.
In terms of defense, we have the Wave Motion Shields.
It will only function for twenty minutes.
But in theory, it should offer ample protection from enemy positron beams.
We'll launch the fighters before the Yamato breaches their warning zone.
The Yamato will act as a decoy,
to draw away the enemy fleet we're anticipating.
The fighters will set a course through Nyx's orbit,
around Charon, then down low, to search for the base.
Once they find it, they will destroy it.
Further, after the Yamato breaks through the enemy fleet,
and arrives off the coast of Pluto,
it will provide support fire from above, to cover the fighters.
I propose another plan.
A long-range shot from the Wave Motion Gun
would destroy the base easily.
We will not use the Wave Motion Gun.
Why not? It's a waste!
Using it would destroy not only the base, but Pluto itself!
I cannot do that.
Why not? What's a planet or two?!
Nanba...
No!
Listen to the Tactical Officer. Why not?
I'm telling you, this will keep the pilots from suffering any losses, as well.
Of course, I don't know if the Yamato even needs a fighter squadron...
What was that?
It's true!
Why, you...
Enough!
We will commence attack on Pluto without the Wave Motion Gun.
It's been decided.
Yes, sir.
Kodai, you are in charge of the fighter squadron.
I-I am, sir?
Yes.
Yes, sir!
Tactical Officer Kodai will take command of the fighter squadron.
We will lead the operation from the combat bridge's CIC.
Tokugawa, go to the combat bridge, and look over the engine.
Understood.
That will be all.
A moment.
You're... Aren't you...
Yamamoto, from accounting. I won't take up much of your time.
Yamamoto...
Then, you piloted that Zero?
I don't know if he's the pilot squad's ace, but that Kato's a jerk.
Team 5 to hangar 1.
Repeat. Team 5 to hangar 1.
Oh, I see...
Then, if you'll excuse me.
Oh, Shima!
Now you can avenge your brother.
I'll do what I can, but that's it.
Take care of the Yamato for me.
Come in.
It's Navigation Officer Shima.
We're almost at the mission zone. Please report to the CIC.
Why did you come here?
You're a hero of the Second Battle of Mars.
And I have always admired you as a sailor.
I lost my father in these seas, where they first attacked us.
So I agree with your plan to attack Pluto.
As Navigation Officer, I swear to make up for the lost time.
I see.
Tactical Officer, I realize the mission is about to commence,
but I'd like to speak with you briefly.
Sure.
But first, there's something I'd like you all to hear.
We have a transfer, from accounting to the fighter squadron.
I've been ordered to transfer into the fighter squadron.
My name is Yamamoto. Nice to meet you all.
I feel like working twice as hard now.
Working twice as hard at what, Sugiyama?
Welcome to the club!
Akira! You...
Akira?
Aren't you Rei?
Excuse me...
This name is read "Akira."
I see...
I didn't realize.
Rei is fine. Everyone calls me that.
All right.
Captain Okita has already approved this.
Jeez...
I'll be handling the pilot and fighter end of the operation.
Alpha will take the northern hemisphere.
Bravo, the southern hemisphere.
After the descent to Pluto,
we'll split into groups of two, to start the operation.
Yamamoto. You'll be in Alpha, with me.
Yes, sir.
I'm sure some of you have lost
family and friends to enemy attacks.
But do not consider dying
to avenge them.
Come back alive. That's an order!
You wanted to speak with me about something?
Nah, it's okay. No need to anymore.
Lt. Kato...
Good luck.
Right!
Lieutenant Kodai.
Thank you for the transfer.
I was impressed by your work on Enceladus.
Don't die out there, Yamamoto.
Yes, sir.
Lt. Kodai, go out and avenge Earth for us.
We're almost to the mission zone.
Deploy the Wave Motion Shields.
Deploying Wave Motion Shields.
Output at eighty percent.
Fighters ready for launch.
Initiating Operation M-2. Lower the Hayabusa!
Cosmo Zeros Alpha 1 and Alpha 2, you are cleared for takeoff.
Alpha 1, roger. Clear for takeoff.
Alpha 2, roger. Clear for takeoff.
Alpha 1 to all fighters.
Maintain radio silence until target is located. Activate ECM.
Good luck out there.
Passing through Nyx's orbit.
It's so quiet...
Is this really enemy space?
Anything on the radar?
No enemy ships sighted.
Maybe they were frightened of the Yamato?
No, this silence feels more threatening.
Mori, keep a close eye on that radar.
Yes, sir.
Captain, if we make it through Charon's orbit
and get Pluto in our sights, all we'd need is the Yamato...
This operation depends on our ability to work with the fighter squad.
We'll wait for Kodai.
What was that light?
Report!
Probably an enemy long-range attack.
Where did they fire from?
I'm not seeing any enemy ships. And that wasn't from Pluto.
Damage to deck 3. Wave Motion Shields penetrated.
Closing bulkheads!
What's going on?
Please don't look!
Inertial control system is down!
Ship interior at zero-g.
The attack came from ten o'clock, port side.
Begin evasive maneuvers.
Hard to port, and move into their blind spot.
Evasive maneuvers. Hard to port!
First shot has hit. Impact confirmed.
Yamato is engaging in evasive maneuvers.
Splendid, Commander Shultz...
Even I, Ganz,
never imagined using the planet bomb launch system as a weapon!
You must consider things from different angles.
On the battlefield, the ability to adapt is always critical.
General Domel taught us that.
However, it's unfortunate that the first strike didn't finish them.
A hunt is something to be savored, Jarletora.
Prepare reflecting satellites for next volley!
<Recharging energy! Quickly!>
<40 seconds until energy charging complete.>
Analysis of the attack's flight path puts this area in their blind spot.
We're safe...
Stay on guard.
They know where the Yamato is.
They're sure to strike again.
Maintain geostationary orbit.
There's a lot of debris.
Do you think yourselves hidden?
Reflecting satellites 7, 13, 28. Deploying reflectors.
Fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
It's the same attack as before.
Wasn't this supposed to be a blind spot?
Radar, where did the attack originate?
I can't find the launch point.
Maintain our position!
We can't... Propulsion's dropping. I can't control it!
We're leaking working fluid from the point of impact!
Shima, land us in the seas of Pluto.
Y-Yes, sir.
Raise the bow!
Preparing to land.
All crew, brace for impact.
Landing complete...
Stay on guard!
Captain, we're approaching the Wave Motion Shields' time limit.
One more of those attacks...
Understood. Have the ship repaired.
Aihara, any word from the fighters?
Nothing yet.
Captain...
May I make a suggestion?
Persistent bastards...
Don't give them a chance to rest.
Ready next round from the Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
Reflecting satellites in position.
Reflecting Satellite Cannon charged.
Yamato, you have fought well.
However, this is the end. Farewell, Yamato!
Directly Above
Powerful energy readings...
Directly overhead!
Directly Above
Episode 5
The Trap on All Sides
The unknown calls to us
Does your courage burn to go there?
We rush on a journey
For everyone to survive together
For happiness
Though there is pain
And sadness
We will not be defeated
Those who know the beautiful Earth
Restore its wonders
Bring it back, bring it back
The road to tomorrow
Not afraid anymore
Determined to reach our destination
The Yamato sinks into the Pluto Sea.
Yamato, rise...
Rise, Yamato!
The people of Earth await your return. It is their last hope.
Open the vents! Raise the Yamato!
Target the hidden enemy base,
and fire a shot into the aurora-filled skies!
Next time: The Sun Sets on Pluto.
There are 361 days left before humanity is extinct.